<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MFFJM</string>
    <string name="cypres_menu_title">MILITARY CYPRES CALCULATOR</string>
    <string name="aircraft_alt_setting">Aircraft Altimeter Setting (inHg/mbar):</string>
    <string name="altimeter_menu_title">ALTIMETER\nCALCULATOR</string>
    <string name="daf_elevation">DAF Elevation (ft MSL):</string>
    <string name="sustained_01">All U.S. Army MFF jumpers will receive SAT within the 24-hour period
        immediately prior to station time of an MFF operation. \n\nPrior to SAT, MFF jumpmasters will ensure
        all jumpers are in the designated uniform, have appropriate equipment, and have their equipment
        properly rigged. This appendix describes the four major areas of SAT for MFF RA-1 jumps.</string>
    <string name="sat_note_first_page"><b>Note:</b> Except for the jumpmaster briefing, SAT will be performance oriented.</string>
    <string name="sat_overview_first_page">At a minimum, MFF SAT will consist of the following:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Jumpmaster Briefing.</b> The jumpmaster briefing will include a manifest call, check of
        identification card and tags, and inspection of the jumper’s uniform and their rigged
        individual equipment.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Aircraft Procedures.</b> Aircraft procedures will include mock door rehearsals and emergency
        procedures. Field expedient mockups can be used. The rehearsal will be performance
        oriented and conducted in the same manner as the actual operation. The actual jumpmaster
            will conduct the rehearsal.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Exit Procedures.</b> Exit procedures will include aircraft emergency procedures, oxygen
        procedures (if used), exit procedures, actions during free-fall, and other emergency
        procedures. The rehearsal will be conducted where all jumpers can observe and hear the
        jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Canopy Control and Landing Procedures.</b> This portion of SAT will include performance oriented training.</string>
    <string name="jumpmaster_briefing_overview">Jumpmasters will brief the outline below to ensure all jumpers understand who the key personnel
        are and also understand the MFF operation, DZ, type of aircraft being jumped, emergency procedures, and the weather conditions.</string>
    <string name="sustained_key_personnel_left">Airborne commander officer in charge/ noncommissioned
        officer in charge. \nJumpmaster. \nAssistant jumpmaster. \nOxygen safety. \nPhysiological technician.
        \nEquipment noncommissioned officer. \nDrop zone safety officer. \nParachute rigger.</string>
    <string name="sustained_key_personnel_right">Malfunction noncommissioned officer. \nDrop zone medic.
        \nDrop zone communicator. \nSafety boat driver. \nSafety boat diver. \nSafety vehicle driver.</string>
    <string name="sustained_op_data_left">Type jump: NT/day/night/water admin/tactical oxygen/CE/weapon. \nDrop altitude.
        \nPull altitude.</string>
    <string name="sustained_op_data_right">Magnetic heading/distance to desired impact point.
        \nDrop zone location on exit.</string>
    <string name="sustained_drop_zone_left">Length.\nWidth.\nDrop zone elevation (mean sea level).
        \nAltimeter/Cybernetic Parachute Release System setting. \nDesired impact point. \nLanding pattern.
        \nAssembly area.</string>
    <string name="sustained_drop_zone_right">Method of marking.\nTerrain description.\nObstacles on/around the drop zone.
        \nTrack of aircraft.\nAlternate landing areas.</string>
    <string name="sustained_aircraft_left">Type.\nAircraft heading.\nHigh-altitude release point.
        \nType of exit.\nExit dispersion.\nExit altitude.</string>
    <string name="sustained_aircraft_right">Number of passes.\nExit order.\nAircraft configuration/seating.
        \nLocation of key personnel.</string>
    <string name="sustained_weather_left">Source of weather data.\nTime/location of weather data.
        \nForecasted winds.\nDirection.\nVelocity.</string>
    <string name="sustained_weather_right">Temperature at exit altitude.\nTemperature at surface altitude.
        \nCeiling/cloud coverage.\nVisibility.\nOther.</string>
    <string name="aircraft_emergencies_on_ground">The following procedures will be used for an emergency prior to takeoff:
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers take all commands from the primary jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers exit the aircraft and assemble 300 meters in a safe direction, as directed by the primary
        jumpmaster. Once assembled, jumpers report to the primary jumpmaster.  </string>
    <string name="crash_landing">The following procedures will be used for an emergency during takeoff to 1,000 feet AGL:
        \n•\t\t\tPrepare for a crash landing. The signal will be six short rings of alarm bell or verbal warning to
        alert jumpers to prepare for a crash landing. One long continuous bell from the aircrew will
        indicate that a crash is imminent.
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers prepare for the crash by remaining seated, fastening their seat belts, and assuming the
        emergency landing position (cover head with arms and brace for impact).
        \n•\t\t\tWait for the aircraft to come to a complete stop; unbuckle.
        \n•\t\t\tExit and assemble upwind 300 meters off the nose of the aircraft or upwind of the aircraft in a
        safe distance and direction indicated by the jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\tConduct a head count, administer first aid, and signal for help.</string>
    <string name="emergency_bailout_low_alt">The jumpmaster will give the emergency bailout signal by extending
        his arm straight up and moving it in a circular motion with index finger pointed. The following procedures
        will be used:
        \n•\t\t\tPrepare for an emergency bailout. The signal will be three short rings of alarm bell or a verbal
        warning will alert jumpers to prepare for an emergency bailout.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster will give the emergency bailout signal by extending his arm over his head with
        the index finger pointed and moving it in a circular motion.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster will then place a clenched fist over his reserve ripcord handle and thrust it out
        to the side, indicating that the jumper will exit on their reserve.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster may issue abbreviated jump commands if time permits.
        \n•\t\t\tOn the jumpmaster’s command, the jumper will conduct a dive exit opposite of the jumper in
        front of him.
        \n•\t\t\tAll jumpers will clear the aircraft and deploy the reserve canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tAll jumpers will complete the canopy controllability check, attempt to land with other jumpers,
        and assemble for a head count.</string>
    <string name="emergency_bailout_high_alt">The jumpmaster will give the emergency bailout signal by extending his
        arm straight up and moving it in a circular motion with index finger pointed. The following procedures will be used:
        \n•\t\t\tPrepare for an emergency bailout. The signal will be three short rings of alarm bell or a verbal
        warning will alert jumpers to prepare for an emergency bailout.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster may issue abbreviated jump commands if time permits.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster will give the emergency bailout signal by extending his arm over his head with
        the index finger pointed and moving it in a circular motion.
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster will then place a clenched fist over his main OTS ripcord handle and thrust it
        out to the side or point to the BOC, indicating that jumpers will exit on their main canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tOn the jumpmaster’s command, the jumper will execute a dive exit opposite of the jumper in
        front of him.
        \n•\t\t\tAll jumpers will clear the aircraft and deploy the main canopy with no more than a 5-second
        delay.
        \n•\t\t\tAll jumpers will complete the canopy controllability check, attempt to land with other jumpers,
        and assemble for a head count.</string>
    <string name="pilot_chute_activation_in_aircraft">With the ramp or doors OPENED or CLOSED, procedures for a
        premature activation of the pilot chute inside the aircraft are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tWith the ramp or doors CLOSED: Shout “PILOT CHUTE,” contain it, and notify the jumpmaster
        (to ensure the ramp or doors do not open). If the pilot chute activates or the container comes
        open, the container will be closed and the jumper will be seated, will fasten his seat belt, and will
        not jump.
        \n•\t\t\tWith the ramp or doors OPEN: Shout “PILOT CHUTE,” attempt to contain it, and notify the
        jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\tOnce the parachute is contained, the jumper will move away from the open exit to a safe area
        forward in the aircraft.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the reserve pilot chute is deployed, the jumper will be moved to the front of the aircraft. He will
        remove his equipment and place the parachute system inside the kit bag. He will fasten his seat
        belt and land with the aircraft.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the pilot chute or parachute is pulled outside the aircraft, the jumper and jumpers in front of
        the jumper must exit immediately.</string>
    <string name="non_oxygen_aircraft_procedures"><b><i>Note:</i></b>  For the purpose of this segment, commands and procedures
        are written in capital letters.
        \nThe following aircraft procedures and jump commands will be used for nonoxygen jumps:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>LOAD AIRCRAFT.</b> Load the aircraft on the jumpmaster’s signal in reverse stick order.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>DON HELMETS. </b>Don helmets and fasten seat belts.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>UNFASTEN SEAT BELTS.</b> At 1,001 feet AGL, unfasten seat belts at the jumpmaster’s
        command. Helmets may be removed at the jumpmaster’s discretion.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>20-MINUTES. </b>At the 20-minute warning, everyone awake and keep eyes on the jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>10-MINUTES. </b>At the 10-minute warning, keep eyes on the jumpmaster and don helmets if removed.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Obtain update on winds.</b> Updated winds from the DZ, expressed in knots.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>CYPRES/PIN CHECK. </b>Jumpers receive a CYPRES and pin check.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>STAND UP. </b>Given 2 minutes from release point. Stand up, face rear of the aircraft, check
        CYPRES and pins on jumper in front of you and give him a thumbs-up, then conduct a check of
        all your handles and equipment.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>MOVE TO THE REAR.</b> Given approximately 1 minute from TOT. Pass signal back, then first
        jumper moves to hinge of ramp or 1 meter from jump door.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>STAND BY.</b> Given approximately 15 seconds from TOT. Return a thumbs-up. First jumper
        moves to edge of ramp or to jump door.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>GO. </b>Given at the release point. Exit as briefed.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>ABORT. </b>Given when release conditions are not favorable. Back up to hinge of ramp and await
        further instructions.
        \n<b><i>Note:</i></b>  If at any time you experience an equipment-related problem, extend your arm toward the center of the
        aircraft and give a thumbs down signal.</string>
    <string name="oxygen_aircraft_procedures"><b><i>Note:</i></b>  For the purpose of this segment, commands and procedures
        are written in capital letters.
        \nThe following aircraft procedures and jump commands will be used for oxygen jumps:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>LOAD AIRCRAFT.</b> Load the aircraft on the jumpmaster’s signal in reverse stick order and—
        \n\t\t•\t\tWait to be seated by the oxygen representative.
        \n\t\t•\t\tReceive console hose from the oxygen representative and connect to console.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>DON HELMETS. </b>Don helmets and fasten seat belts.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>UNFASTEN SEAT BELTS.</b> At 1,001 feet AGL, unfasten seat belts at the jumpmaster’s command.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>20-MINUTES. </b>At the 20-minute warning, everyone awake and keep eyes on the jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>10-MINUTES. </b>At the 10-minute warning, keep eyes on the jumpmaster.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Obtain update on winds.</b> Updated winds from the DZ, expressed in knots.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>CYPRES/PIN CHECK. </b>Jumpers receive a CYPRES and pin check.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>MASK.</b> On the command MASK:
        \n\t\t•\t\tConnect right side oxygen fitting.
        \n\t\t•\t\tEnsure you have a positive oxygen flow and extend a thumbs-up to the center of the aircraft.
        Hold the signal until the jumpmaster checks the entire aircraft and return a thumbs-up.
        Follow this procedure every time the jumpmaster initiates an oxygen check.
        \n<b><i>Note:</i></b>  Do not remove helmets during oxygen operations. Clear goggles must be worn during oxygen jump
        operations. If at any time you experience oxygen-related problems, extend your arm, palm down, toward the
        center of the aircraft.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>STAND UP. </b>Stand up, face the rear of the aircraft, check CYPRES, pins, and the oxygen bottle
        of the jumper to your front ensuring they are on and have sufficient pressure. (Gauge needle
        should be at 1 or above. Notify the jumpmaster, assistant jumpmaster, or oxygen representative
        of any deficiencies that are identified.) Check your handles and equipment; place right hand on
        the quick disconnect.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>MOVE TO THE REAR.</b> Given approximately 1 minute from TOT. Pass signal back. The oxygen
        representative, assistant jumpmaster, and/or jumper will disconnect from the console and ensure
        you have a positive flow of oxygen. The first jumper moves to the hinge of ramp or 1 meter from
        jump door.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>STAND BY.</b> Given approximately 15 seconds from TOT. Return a thumbs-up. First jumper
        moves to edge of ramp or to the jump door.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>GO. </b>Given at the release point. Exit as briefed.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>ABORT. </b>Given when release conditions are not favorable. Back up to hinge of ramp or 1 meter
        from the open door and await further instructions.
        \n<b>After Exiting:</b>
        \n\t\t•\t\tLeave the mask connected until landing.
        \n\t\t•\t\tAfter landing, turn off the oxygen bottle and disconnect the mask. Place mask in the
        container and replace red caps on all fittings.</string>
    <string name="altimeter_failure_prior_to_exit">If the jumper’s altimeter fails on the aircraft, use the following procedures:
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumper will inform a jumpmaster and the defective altimeter will be exchanged with an
        onboard spare.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the onboard spare is in use or both altimeters fail prior to exit, the jumper will be moved to the
        front of the aircraft to a safe location, remain seated, and air land with the aircraft.
        \n<b><i>Note:</i></b> Even with an altimeter failure, the jumpmaster can command the jumper to exit the aircraft in an
        emergency situation.</string>
    <string name="equipment_malfunction">Procedures for an equipment malfunction on the aircraft are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tJumper gets the attention of the jumpmaster by extending his arm straight out with his thumb
        pointing down.
        \n•\t\t\tJumpmaster will correct the malfunction or make the determination for the jumper to land with
        the aircraft.</string>
    <string name="exit_procedures_subtitle">As per jumpmaster’s brief, jumpers will exit on a designated heading
        without losing stability in a controlled exit by executing a dive exit, poise exit, or box-man exit.
        Jumpmasters will cover all emergency procedures in this section.</string>
    <string name="emergency_procedures_on_exit">Procedures for a jumper in tow by equipment are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tThe jumpmaster will try to free the hung equipment or cut the jumper free. As the jumper falls
        free, he will attempt to get into a good exit position. If the main parachute fails to deploy when
        pulled, the jumper will immediately execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the jumper is unconscious, the jumpmaster will attempt to pull the jumper inside the aircraft.</string>
    <string name="collision_on_exit">Procedures for a collision on exit are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tJumper will maintain his arch and gently push off the other jumper with an open hand.
        \n•\t\t\tAll jumpers involved will regain their stability, check their altimeter, check their ripcord handles,
        and continue the free-fall as planned.
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers making contact with other jumpers during exit will not grab any part of the other jumper
        or equipment if contact is made.</string>
    <string name="emergencies_in_freefall">Procedures for emergencies during free-fall are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Spinning.</b> Arch, check your hands and feet, counter the spin and maintain altitude awareness.
        If spinning out of control and unable to maintain altitude awareness, wave off and pull.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Tumbling.</b> Arch, keep your head up, check your hands and feet, and maintain altitude
        awareness. If tumbling out of control and unable to maintain altitude awareness, wave off and pull.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Entering a Cloud or Loss of Visibility.</b> Stop all movement and return to a stable, relaxed arch.
        Maintain altitude awareness. Pull at the prescribed altitude even if you are still in the cloud.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Lost or Loose Goggles.</b> If your goggles become loose or dislodged during free-fall, make one
        attempt to replace them. If unsuccessful, continue the free-fall as planned. Squint your eyes in
        order to maintain your vision. Maintain altitude awareness and pull at the prescribed altitude.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Altimeter Failure or Lost Altimeter During Free-Fall.</b> During both day and night operations,
        observe other jumpers and pull when they do. If no other jumpers can be observed, clear your
        air space, wave off, and pull your main ripcord immediately.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Rucksack Shifts.</b> Counter any turn caused by the rucksack shifting in free-fall by turning in the
        opposite direction. If the rucksack strap moves below his knee, the jumper makes one attempt
        to replace it while maintaining stability. If the jumper loses altitude awareness and is unable to
        gain control, he will wave off and pull the main OTS ripcord or deploy the hand-deployed pilot
        chute from the BOC.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Collision Avoidance During Free-Fall.</b> Jumpers—
        \n\t\t•\t\tRemember that the lower jumper has the right-of-way.
        \n\t\t•\t\tNever get over the top of another jumper.
        \n\t\t•\t\tUse forward glide, back slide, or side slide to get off a jumper’s back.</string>
    <string name="premature_activation_freefall">In the event of a premature activation of a parachute in free-fall,
        the jumper must first determine which parachute has activated. Procedures for premature activation of a parachute
        in free-fall are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Premature Opening: Main Parachute.</b> If the jumper has a premature opening of the main
        parachute, he will be able to determine if it is the main parachute by the three-ring assembly,
        deployment bag, and pilot chute. The jumper will conduct a controllability check and continue as
        planned.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Premature Opening: Reserve Parachute.</b> If the jumper has a premature opening of the reserve
        parachute, he will be able to determine if it is the reserve parachute by NO three-ring assembly
        (snowman) on reserve risers, NO deployment bag, NO pilot chute, NO trim tabs on risers, center
        of reserve slider will have a mesh, and the bottom skin of the reserve canopy will have square
        holes. The jumper will conduct postopening procedures and continue the jump as planned. The
        jumper will not activate the main parachute.</string>
    <string name="pull_priorities">Procedures for main canopy deployment during free-fall are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Pull.</b>
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Never sacrifice altitude for stability.</b>
        \n<b>For OTS Ripcord.</b> At the prescribed pull altitude, maintain your ARCH, use head tilt method to LOOK at the
        main ripcord and with the right hand, TRACE the main ripcord cable housing to the main ripcord handle while
        moving your left hand into the counter position. PULL the ripcord to full-arm extension and CHECK over the
        right shoulder to ensure the pilot chute has launched.
        \n<b>For BOC with Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute.</b> At the prescribed pull altitude, maintain your ARCH, maintain
        positive legs, and keep head and eyes up on the horizon. The jumper reaches and grabs the handle of the hand-deployed
        pilot chute with his right hand while countering with the left hand. PULL the hand-deployed pilot chute
        out of the BOC pouch and turn the right hand palm to the rear, extending the right arm to full-arm extension to
        RELEASE the hand-deployed pilot chute. CHECK over the right shoulder to ensure the pilot chute has launched.</string>
    <string name="canopy_control_procedures">Upon canopy deployment, these procedures will be followed:
        \n•\t\t\tPostopening: Check canopy, grasp rear risers, and clear air space.
        \n•\t\t\tRiser turn toward DZ.
        \n•\t\t\tUnstow toggles, gain canopy control, and assume position in formation.
        \n•\t\t\tReach up and collapse slider. Conduct a canopy controllability check (3 S’s: Square, Stable, and
        Serviceable).
        \n•\t\t\tIf applicable, position HAHO seat under buttocks.</string>
    <string name="canopy_flight">After canopy deployment, the jumper will use the following procedures during canopy flight:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Full Flight.</b> Arms fully extended. Maximizes forward airspeed.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Quarter Brakes.</b> Toggles at eye level. Slowest descent rate.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Half Brakes.</b> Toggles at chest level. Decreases forward airspeed by half.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Full Brakes.</b> Toggles at lowest possible level. No forward airspeed.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Full Flight Turn.</b> Toggle pulled to full arms extension. Fast and steep turn.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Half Brake Turn.</b> During half brakes, pull to full-arm extension the direction you want to turn
        while maintaining half-braked opposite toggle. Turn will be slow and flat.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Front Riser Turn.</b> Faster and steeper.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Rear Riser Turn.</b> Faster and flatter.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Holding.</b> Into the wind.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Running.</b> With the wind.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Crabbing.</b> Crossing wind line at an angle.</string>
    <string name="postexit_emergency_procedures">Malfunction types are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>High-Speed Malfunction.</b> When the ripcord has been pulled, the deployment bag remains in
        the container.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Low-speed Malfunction.</b> Container assembly opens, but canopy does not fully or properly deploy.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Cutaway Decision Altitude.</b> 2,500 feet AGL for high-speed and low-speed malfunction.</string>
    <string name="cutaway_procedures_ots">Once you initiate the CUTAWAY sequence, continue it through to completion.
        Cutaway procedures for OTS ripcord are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tTHROWAWAY main ripcord handle.
        \n•\t\t\tARCH after assuming a hard-arch body position.
        \n•\t\t\tCOUNTER with left hand.
        \n•\t\t\tLOOK to identify the red cutaway pillow on the right main lift web, chest high, inboard.
        \n•\t\t\tGRAB the red cutaway pillow with your right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tPULL the red cutaway pillow to full-arm extension.
        \n•\t\t\tTHROW AWAY the red cutaway pillow.
        \n•\t\t\tCOUNTER with right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tLOOK to identify the yellow reserve ripcord handle on the left main lift web, chest high, inboard.
        \n•\t\t\tGRAB the yellow reserve ripcord handle with your left hand.
        \n•\t\t\tPULL the yellow reserve ripcord handle to full-arm extension.
        \n•\t\t\tTHROW AWAY the yellow reserve ripcord handle.
        \n•\t\t\tCHECK over right shoulder to ensure the reserve pilot chute deploys.</string>
    <string name="cutaway_procedures_boc">Once you initiate the CUTAWAY sequence, continue it through to completion.
        Cutaway procedures for the BOC hand-deployed pilot chute are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tARCH after assuming a hard-arch body position.
        \n•\t\t\tCOUNTER with left hand.
        \n•\t\t\tLOOK to identify the red cutaway pillow on the right main lift web, chest high, inboard.
        \n•\t\t\tGRAB the red cutaway pillow with your right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tPULL the red cutaway pillow to full-arm extension.
        \n•\t\t\tTHROW AWAY the red cutaway pillow.
        \n•\t\t\tCOUNTER with right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tLOOK to identify the yellow reserve ripcord handle on the left main lift web, chest high, inboard.
        \n•\t\t\tGRAB the yellow reserve ripcord handle with your left hand.
        \n•\t\t\tPULL the yellow reserve ripcord handle to full-arm extension.
        \n•\t\t\tTHROW AWAY the yellow reserve ripcord handle.
        \n•\t\t\tCHECK over right shoulder to ensure the reserve pilot chute deploys.</string>
    <string name="total_malfunction">Only two attempts will be made to clear the total malfunctions listed below.
        \n<b><i>Note:</i></b> Your first attempt is made during normal pull procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Hard Ripcord Pull.</b>  For OTS ripcord, if the initial pull is unsuccessful, reach across with the left
        hand in a punching motion and push the right hand and ripcord out. If this does not pull the
        ripcord, execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Hard Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute Pull.</b>  For BOC, if the initial pull is unsuccessful, use right
        elbow on the side of the container as leverage when pulling the pilot chute from the BOC. If the
        jumper is unsuccessful, he will execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Floating Ripcord.</b>  Look at the ripcord stow pocket. Locate the ripcord housing with the
        hand. Locate the ripcord cable, which should be protruding from the housing. Pull the cable. If
        this attempt is unsuccessful, execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Failure to Locate the BOC Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute Handle.</b>  Jumper will only make two
        attempts to locate the hand-deployed pilot chute handle. If unsuccessful, the jumper will execute
        cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Pack Closure.</b>  After the jumper pulls the ripcord, he checks over the right shoulder. If no pilot
        chute deploys, he immediately checks over the right shoulder again. If this does not correct the
        problem, execute cutaway procedures.</string>
    <string name="partial_malfunction">The below malfunctions are partial malfunctions; the jumper will execute cutaway
        procedures immediately. NO attempt will be made to clear these partial malfunctions:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Horseshoe.</b> Pilot chute, parachute, or suspension lines are caught on you or your equipment.
        Execute cutaway procedures immediately.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Bag Lock.</b> Canopy remains in deployment bag after pulling the main OTS ripcord or releasing
        the main hand-deployed pilot chute. Execute cutaway procedures immediately.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Line-Over.</b> Suspension line(s) routed over the canopy causing a distorted or bowtie canopy.
        Execute cutaway procedures immediately.</string>
    <string name="deployment_emergencies">These procedures will be followed to correct the below actions during
        deployment emergencies:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Hard Ripcord Pull (Main OTS Ripcord).</b> If the jumper pulls the main ripcord and the pull is
        unsuccessful, the jumper will come across with the left hand in a punching motion and push the
        right hand and ripcord out. If still unsuccessful, the jumper will perform cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Hard Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute Pull (BOC).</b> If the initial pull is unsuccessful, the jumper will
        use his right elbow on the side of the container as leverage when pulling the pilot chute from the
        BOC. If the jumper is unsuccessful, he will execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Floating Ripcord or Unable to See Ripcord (OTS Ripcord).</b> The jumper will maintain arch
        and look at the OTS ripcord pocket. If the jumper is unable to see the ripcord or if it is floating,
        he will locate the cable housing on his right shoulder with his right hand. The jumper will trace
        the cable housing down to where the ripcord cable protrudes out. He will then make a circle with
        his index finger and thumb around the cable and pull the cable to full-arm extension. The jumper
        will only make one attempt; if unsuccessful, he will perform cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Failure to Locate Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute Handle (BOC).</b> The jumper will only make two
        attempts to locate the hand-deployed pilot chute handle. If unsuccessful, he will execute cutaway
        procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Pilot Chute Entangled with Right Arm (BOC).</b> If the pilot chute is entangled with the right arm,
        the jumper will attempt to untangle it by using a swimming motion to remove the bridle from his
        arm. If unsuccessful, he will perform cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Pack Closure.</b> The jumper pulls the OTS ripcord or releases the hand-deployed pilot chute
        (BOC) and checks over his right shoulder. If no pilot chute deploys, he immediately checks over
        the right shoulder again. If this does not correct the malfunction, he will execute cutaway
        procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Hand-Deployed Pilot Chute in Tow (BOC).</b> In the event the main container assembly does not
        open after the hand-deployed pilot chute has been released, the jumper executes cutaway
        procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Pilot Chute Hesitation.</b>  The jumper looks over the right shoulder to disrupt the partial vacuum
        to clear the burble. If the main parachute does not deploy, the jumper will perform cutaway
        procedures.</string>
    <string name="postopening_emergency_procedures">With all malfunctions, a canopy controllability check is required
        after appropriate actions are taken as per the malfunction. Postopening emergency problems that require a
        visual and/or canopy controllability check are as follows:
        \n•\t\t\tLook left; turn left 90 degrees.
        \n•\t\t\tLook right; turn right 90 degrees.
        \n•\t\t\tDetermine the flare point.
        \n•\t\t\t50-percent Rule: If the canopy requires 50-percent opposite toggle to counter a turn or if the
        canopy stalls prior to 50-percent brakes, the canopy is uncontrollable.
        <b><i>Note:</i></b> Make only two attempts to clear a malfunction. Cutaway procedures must be
        initiated by 2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="streamer_snivel">The jumper will reach up and release the brakes and pull the toggles down to full-brakes
        position for 3 to 4 seconds. The jumper will then let up slowly to 50-percent brake setting. If the malfunction
        is not clear, the jumper will make one more attempt to pull the toggles down to full-brakes position for 3 to 4
        seconds. If the malfunction still has not cleared, the jumper will perform cutaway procedures.</string>
    <string name="line_twists">Follow these procedures for line twists:
        \n•\t\t\tReach up with both hands, thumbs pointed down, and separate the risers.
        \n•\t\t\tUse a bicycling motion or kick both legs in the opposite direction of the twist to untwist the lines.
        \n•\t\t\tDo not unstow the brakes until line twists are cleared.
        \n•\t\t\tMaintain altitude awareness and if unable to clear twists or the twists are still above the cascades
        by 2,500 feet AGL, initiate cutaway procedures.</string>
    <string name="hung_slider">If the slider remains above the cascades, it will deform the canopy and degrade lift and
        drive performance to an unacceptable level. Follow these procedures for a hung slider:
        \n•\t\t\tPump both rear risers vigorously to move the slider downward.
        \n•\t\t\tRelease both sets of toggles and pump vigorously to bring the slider down completely if the rear
        risers are not successful. The slider must travel at least half way down, past the suspension line
        cascades, before attempting a canopy controllability check.
        \n•\t\t\tIf unable to clear the slider past the cascades or pass a canopy controllability check, initiate
        cutaway procedures by 2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="closed_end_cells">Follow these procedures for closed end cells:
        \n•\t\t\tPull toggles down to full-brake position and hold for 4 seconds and let up quickly.
        \n•\t\t\tRepeat the procedure if end cells do not open.
        \n•\t\t\tConduct a canopy controllability check. Use the 50-percent rule if necessary. Consider wind,
        turbulence, distance, and condition of the DZ if canopy barely passes the test. If the canopy is
        controllable, fly and land as planned.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy is uncontrollable or does not pass the test, initiate cutaway procedures by
        2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="pilot_chute_over_nose">Follow these procedures for drogue pilot chute over the nose:
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to flip the pilot chute back over the top of the canopy by bringing toggles to full brakes
        (flaring) and letting the toggles up abruptly.
        \n•\t\t\tConduct a canopy controllability check 50-percent rule if necessary.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy is controllable, fly and land as planned.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy is uncontrollable, initiate cutaway procedures by 2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="tension_knots">Follow these procedures for tension knots:
        \n•\t\t\tStop the turn with opposite rear riser input.
        \n•\t\t\tSnap the risers of the affected line group by pulling down and releasing.
        \n•\t\t\tAfter two attempts, release the toggles and come to a full brake position, hold for 3 to 4 seconds,
        then let up slowly.
        \n•\t\t\tAfter two attempts, conduct a canopy controllability check. If the canopy is controllable, fly and
        land as planned.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy is uncontrollable, initiate cutaway procedures by 2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="broken_suspension_lines">If suspension lines (A, B, C, D) break during opening,
        follow these procedures:
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Stop the Turn with Rear Riser Input.</b> It may be difficult to identify the broken lines and the
        canopy may or may not look deformed. If there are two or more lines broken or if there are any
        A-lines broken, immediately perform cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Conduct a Canopy Controllability Check.</b> Use the 50-percent rule if necessary. Consider
        wind, turbulence, distance, and condition of the DZ. If the canopy is controllable, fly and land as
        planned. If the canopy is uncontrollable, initiate cutaway procedures by 2,500 feet AGL.</string>
    <string name="rips_or_tears">If you notice rips or tears in the bottom skin of the canopy during canopy check,
        follow these procedures:
        \n•\t\t\tIf possible, check your rate of descent with other jumpers.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are descending faster than the other jumpers, execute cutaway procedures.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are not descending faster than other jumpers, conduct a canopy controllability check.
        \n•\t\t\tIf there is a rip or tear on the top skin of the canopy, execute cutaway procedures.</string>
    <string name="premature_break_release">Follow these procedures for a premature brake release:
        \n•\t\t\tStop the turn with rear riser input (the released side).
        \n•\t\t\tImmediately release the other toggle control line.
        \n•\t\t\tConduct a canopy controllability check. If the canopy is uncontrollable, initiate cutaway
        procedures by 2,500 feet.</string>
    <string name="broken_control_lines">Follow these procedures for broken control line(s):
        \n•\t\t\tStop the turn using the opposite rear riser.
        \n•\t\t\tRelease the other control line.
        \n•\t\t\tSteer using the good control line and opposite rear riser.
        \n•\t\t\tDetermine the flare point at a safe altitude using only the rear risers; note that the canopy
        responds much quicker while using the rear risers.
        \n•\t\t\tFlare using both rear risers only.</string>
    <string name="canopy_control_procedures_subtitle">Jumpmasters will cover all canopy control and landing procedures in this section.</string>
    <string name="entering_a_cloud_under_canopy">The jumper will follow these procedures when entering a cloud:
        \n•\t\t\tStops all turns and stays alert.
        \n•\t\t\tUses 50-percent brakes.
        \n•\t\t\tMaintains heading and picks up reference points if possible prior to entering the cloud.
        \n•\t\t\tMaintains altitude and air awareness.</string>
    <string name="dual_canopy_intro">If both the main and reserve canopies deploy on exit, the jumper identifies
        the configuration: side-by-side, bi-plane, in between, or down plane.</string>
    <string name="side_by_side">•\t\t\tEnsure canopies are not entangled by tracing all eight risers
        through the sliders to respective lines and canopies. Risers should cross properly.
        \n•\t\t\tDo not release the brakes on either canopy. If brakes released on one canopy, fly at half brakes
        to match forward speed of the other canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tIf canopies are not entangled, place the left hand on the left rear riser of the left canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tPlace the right hand on the red cutaway pillow.
        \n•\t\t\tSeparate the canopies into a down plane with the left hand on the left rear riser of the left canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tPeel and pull the red cutaway pillow to full-arm extension and let go of the riser and cutaway
        handle simultaneously.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopies are entangled, or if unsure whether they are entangled, or below 1,000 feet AGL, steer
        the best-looking canopy with the rear risers; gently turn toward the other canopy to prevent a downplane
        configuration; do not attempt to flare and be prepared for a parachutist landing fall (PLF).</string>
    <string name="bi_plane">•\t\t\tEnsure canopies are not entangled by tracing all eight risers through their sliders to respective
        lines and canopies. Risers should cross properly.
        \n•\t\t\tSeparate canopies into a side by side.
        \n•\t\t\tUse left rear riser of the left canopy to separate canopies into a down plane.
        \n•\t\t\tRelease the rear riser with the left hand while pulling the red cutaway pillow with the right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopies are entangled or below 1,000 feet AGL, steer the front canopy with the rear risers,
        making all turns gently and the trail canopy will follow along.
        \n•\t\t\tMake all turns gently in either direction, preventing canopies from going into a down plane.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to steer into the wind.
        \n•\t\t\tDo not attempt to flare and be prepared to conduct a PLF.</string>
    <string name="in_between">•\t\t\tEnsure canopies are not entangled by tracing all eight risers through their sliders to respective
        lines and canopies. Risers should cross properly.
        \n•\t\t\tSeparate canopies into a side by side.
        \n•\t\t\tUse left rear riser of the left canopy to separate canopies into a down plane.
        \n•\t\t\tRelease the rear riser with the left hand while pulling the red cutaway pillow with the right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopies are entangled or below 1,000 feet AGL, steer the front canopy with the rear risers,
        making all turns gently and the trail canopy will follow along.
        \n•\t\t\tMake all turns gently in either direction, preventing canopies from going into a down plane.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to steer into the wind.
        \n•\t\t\tDo not attempt to flare and be prepared to conduct a PLF.</string>
    <string name="down_plane">•\t\t\tEnsure canopies are not entangled by tracing all eight risers through their sliders to respective
        lines and canopies. Risers should cross properly.
        \n•\t\t\tPull the red cutaway pillow with the right hand.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopies are entangled, or if unsure whether they are entangled, or below 1,000 feet AGL,
        steer canopies toward each other with rear risers to get them into a side-by-side configuration.
        It may require a continuous effort all the way to the ground to keep canopies together.
        \n•\t\t\tDo not attempt to flare and be prepared to conduct a PLF.</string>
    <string name="partially_deployed_reserve">•\t\t\tDo not unstow brakes. If brakes have already been unstowed, slow the main to prevent the
        reserve from fully deploying.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to pull in the reserve deployment bag and contain it in your arms.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy begins to inflate, make sure that the suspension lines or risers do not become
        entangled with you or your equipment.
        \n•\t\t\tLet the canopies settle into a configuration, continuously inspecting for entanglements. Follow
        the procedures for that configuration.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the reserve is still in the deployment bag, carefully gather and coil the suspension lines in one
        hand while lifting the bagged canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to prevent the locking stows from popping open and allowing the reserve canopy to slide
        out of the deployment bag.
        \n•\t\t\tContinue until the bagged canopy is in hand. Keep a firm grip on the bagged canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tSteer by leaning in the harness or reaching up with one hand to make rear riser turns.
        \n•\t\t\tAt 15 feet AGL, drop the bagged canopy to the ground and flare the canopy on rear risers. Be
        prepared to conduct a PLF.</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_overview">Follow these procedures for entanglements with another jumper:
        \n•\t\t\tAlways attempt to steer clear of other jumpers by turning away.
        \n•\t\t\tLower jumper has the right of way.
        \n•\t\t\tIf a collision with another jumper is imminent, steer to avoid body-to-body contact. Assume the
        modified spread-eagle position.
        \n•\t\t\tProtect your cutaway pillows with your left arm and attempt to bounce off.
        \n•\t\t\tIf line entanglement occurs, stay calm and do not grab cutaway pillows.
        \n•\t\t\tCheck altitude and look for the other jumper.
        \n•\t\t\tAssess the situation before acting in any way.
        \n•\t\t\tCommunicate altitude and positive commands only.
        \n•\t\t\tNever say “cutaway” unless you are telling the other jumper to execute cutaway procedures. If
        you intend to cutaway, use the words, “I’m executing emergency procedures.”</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_over_2000">Follow these procedures for entanglements above 2,000 feet AGL:
        \n•\t\t\tIf the higher jumper has a good canopy, that jumper should attempt to clear the entanglement
        while protecting emergency pillows.
        \n•\t\t\tFollow your lines out of the entanglement if possible.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the entanglement can be cleared, the lower canopy should re-inflate within 150 to 200 feet.
        Both jumpers should complete a canopy controllability check and inspect their parachute and
        harness thoroughly for damage, then decide whether it is safe to continue to fly and land.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy cannot be cleared, the engulfed jumper fails to respond or appears to be going
        unconscious, or the altitude is approaching 2,000 feet AGL, the lower jumper should
        communicate his intention to cutaway by saying “2,000 feet, I’m executing emergency
        procedures,” then initiate cutaway procedures by 2,000 feet AGL after disconnecting his RSL.
        \n•\t\t\tThe higher jumper should clear the canopy from his face and controls so that he can see and
        steer.
        \n•\t\t\tHe should continue to clear the canopy if possible, keeping his cutaway pillows protected.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the canopy cannot be cleared safely, he should fly slowly with brakes to diminish the other
        canopies drag and potential for interference in flight and control.</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_1000_to_2000">Follow these procedures for entanglements between 2,000 feet AGL and 1,000 feet AGL:
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers should communicate altitudes and positive commands, such as “1,500 feet, hold onto
        me” or “1,000 feet, I got you”.
        \n•\t\t\tThe lower jumper has two options. He can perform cutaway procedures after disconnecting his
        RSL or land with the higher jumper.
        \n•\t\t\tIf the lower jumper decides to land with the higher jumper, the lower jumper should jettison his
        equipment if worn.
        \n•\t\t\tThe higher jumper should maintain control of the lower parachutist and fly final approach at half
        brakes if possible.
        \n•\t\t\tHigher jumper lands at half brakes; both jumpers should execute a PLF.</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_under_1000">Follow these procedures for entanglements below 1,000 feet AGL:
        \n•\t\t\tThe higher jumper should make every effort to maintain the lower jumper’s canopy.
        \n•\t\t\tThe higher jumper should maintain control of the lower jumper and fly final approach at half
        brakes if possible.
        \n•\t\t\tThe lower jumper should jettison combat equipment if worn.
        \n•\t\t\tBoth jumpers need to be prepared to execute a PLF.</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_no_good_chutes">Follow these procedures for entanglements when neither jumper has a good canopy:
        \n•\t\t\tJumpers should attempt to establish communication such as altitudes and positive commands.
        \n•\t\t\tIf both canopies are uncontrollable and/or collapsed, it may be difficult to establish which jumper
        is higher and which is lower and it may be alternating repeatedly.
        \n•\t\t\tIf a jumper is entangled in lines, that jumper should attempt to free himself and cutaway first.
        \n•\t\t\tThe lower jumper should cutaway after the higher jumper.
        \n•\t\t\tThe higher jumper could be fatally engulfed in the lower jumper’s lines and canopy if the lower
        jumper were to cutaway first.
        \n•\t\t\tIf impact with the ground is imminent, both jumpers should deploy their reserve to increase the
        amount of fabric exposed and the extra drag created.
        \n•\t\t\tIf both reserve canopies deploy, both jumpers perform cutaway procedures to clear from
        entanglement to prevent a down plane.</string>
    <string name="canopy_entanglements_unclear_traffic_pattern">Follow these procedures for entanglements of an unclear traffic pattern:
        \n•\t\t\tStay alert and keep your air space clear.
        \n•\t\t\tMaintain 25 meters horizontally and vertically. (Low man has the right of way.)
        \n•\t\t\tOffset canopies; do not fly directly behind another canopy as it causes turbulence.
        \n•\t\t\tAssess the situation and move into formation or get on the wind line and establish the traffic
        pattern.
        \n•\t\t\tFollow the low man or lead the group if you are the low man.
        \n•\t\t\tStay upwind and use the 60-degree method to reach intended target.
        \n•\t\t\tKeep your options open and look for alternate landing areas en route to the DZ. Set up the
        pattern so that the entire group can be into the wind by 300 feet AGL.
        \n•\t\t\tWhen flying through clouds, come to half brakes and maintain your heading and altitude
        awareness until you pass through the clouds. Keep a sharp lookout for other jumpers.</string>
    <string name="landing_pattern">Components of the pattern include holding area, downwind leg, base leg, and final approach.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Downwind Leg.</b> Enter the landing pattern at 900 feet AGL. Offset from where you want to land
        60-degree angle (dependent upon winds). Check lowering line. Fly the landing pattern at quarter
        to half brakes making no radical turns.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Base Leg.</b> Turn onto the base leg (crosswind) at approximately 600 feet AGL. Adjust the angle
        (upwind or downwind) if needed, so that when you turn onto final approach you can land at the
        desired impact point.
        \n•\t\t\t<b>Final Approach.</b> Turn onto final approach (into the wind) so that you are facing upwind by
        300 feet AGL and in normal wind conditions at a 60-degree angle. Continue to fly the canopy by
        applying brakes as needed and making heading adjustments of no more than 45 degrees with
        half brakes. Once on final, clear airspace below and lower combat equipment at 200 to
        100 feet AGL. Be prepared to counter the weight shift.
        \nIf your combat equipment has not been lowered by 100 feet AGL, you will land with your equipment attached.</string>
    <string name="landing_overview">Follow these procedures for landing:
        \n•\t\t\tAt 200 feet AGL, go to full flight to fully inflate the canopy and generate speed for landing.
        \n•\t\t\tInitiate the flare between 10 to 15 feet AGL depending on the wind speed. Higher winds
        (11 to 18 knots) flare lower; lower winds (0 to 10 knots) flare higher. If you flare too high, hold
        toggles in the full brake position and be prepared to do a PLF. Do not use combat equipment as
        a flare indicator.
        \n•\t\t\tContinue to give toggle input as needed to counter gusts and keep the canopy over your head.
        \n•\t\t\tAfter landing, push risers to one side or pull one toggle to collapse the canopy. Follow SOPs for
        assembly procedures.
        \nFor night landings, go to full brake position at approximately 100 feet AGL, look to the horizon, keep your feet
        and knees together, and execute a PLF.</string>
    <string name="tree_landings">Attempt to steer away. If unable to avoid trees:
        \n•\t\t\tIf you have already lowered your combat equipment, jettison it. If not, leave it attached for added
        protection.
        \n•\t\t\tKeep your goggles over your eyes and oxygen mask on if worn.
        \n•\t\t\tTurn the canopy into the wind and attempt a vertical descent between the trees if growth is
        sparse. If dense trees, attempt to cap your canopy on top of the trees or catch the canopy on
        the thickest branches.
        \n•\t\t\tProtect your face with your forearms.
        \n•\t\t\tKeep your feet and knees together and be prepared to execute a PLF.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are suspended and cannot climb down, wait for assistance.</string>
    <string name="water_landings">Attempt to steer away. If unable to avoid water:
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to land as close to shore as possible.
        \n•\t\t\tJettison your combat equipment and oxygen mask if worn.
        \n•\t\t\tUnhook your RSL; unfasten your chest strap and waistband.
        \n•\t\t\tLand into the wind and flare as normal. Be prepared to do a PLF in case the water is shallow.
        \n•\t\t\tAfter you have entered the water, release your leg straps, arch out of the harness, and swim
        free of the harness and suspension lines.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are being dragged, pull the red cutaway pillow.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are trapped under the canopy, follow a seam to the edge. If you need to breathe, form a
        triangle with your hands, push up on the fabric enough to create an air pocket.</string>
    <string name="wire_landings">Attempt to steer away. If unable to avoid wires:
        \n•\t\t\tDisconnect your RSL.
        \n•\t\t\tJettison your combat equipment and turn off your oxygen if worn.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to parallel the wires in a braked position to attain a vertical descent through the wires.
        Be prepared to do a PLF in case you pass through the wires.
        \n•\t\t\tIf contact with the ground is made, cutaway the main canopy and move away.
        \n•\t\t\tIf suspended, remain motionless until the power is cut off. Do not let anyone touch you and do
        not cutaway.</string>
    <string name="high_wind_landings">•\t\t\tAt 1,500 feet AGL, disconnect your RSL.
        \n•\t\t\tAs soon as your feet touch the ground, release one toggle and pull the other toggle hand over
        hand until the canopy collapses.
        \n•\t\t\tPivot in the direction of the pulled toggle.
        \n•\t\t\tAttempt to contain the tail of the canopy.</string>
    <string name="recovery_from_a_drag">•\t\t\tRelease one toggle completely.
        \n•\t\t\tPull the other toggle and steering line in hand over hand until the canopy collapses or canopy
        fabric is in hand.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you cannot get to your feet or collapse the canopy because of injury or other issues, disconnect
        the RSL (if not already disconnected), and pull the red cutaway pillow.</string>
    <string name="dust_devils">•\t\t\tIf you fly through a dust devil, go to full flight in an attempt to build speed.
        Be prepared to execute a PLF if close to the ground. If you land and are overtaken by a dust devil, gather up as much
        canopy as possible and lay down on it.
        \n•\t\t\tAfter landing if control of the canopy is lost, ensure the RSL is disconnected and pull the red
        cutaway pillow.</string>
    <string name="obstacles_on_drop_zone">•\t\t\tAttempt to steer away. Look away; steer away.
        \n•\t\t\tIf you are unable to steer clear, make contact with both feet and execute a PLF.</string>
    <string name="assembly_procedures">Assembly procedures for administrative and tactical jumps will be explained to all jumpers.
        \n•\t\t\tAdministrative.
        \n•\t\t\tTactical.</string>
    <string name="haho_procedures">•\t\t\tCheck in.
        \n•\t\t\tIdentify the low man, number 2 man, and high man. Low man drives to the DZ, taking control
        cues from the number 2 and high man.</string>
    <string name="bundle_procedures">•\t\t\tDuty positions (bundle safety/bundle pusher/loadmaster).
        \n•\t\t\tComplete bundle operation (timeline).
        \n•\t\t\tJumper’s actions on exit, under canopy, and landing.
        \n•\t\t\tCollision or entanglement emergency procedures with the bundle.</string>

</resources>

